Contact

williamtang2001@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/williamtangjx (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Bloomberg
Problem Solving
Microsoft Excel

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Chinese (Limited Working)

Certifications

Verified Certificate for Sustainable Financial Services on Web 3.0

Adjunct Affiliate Trainer

Verified Certificate for Building Financial Services on Web 3.0

Web 3.0 Knowledge Certificate in Financial Services

Verified Certificate for Designing Financial Services on Web 3.0

Honors-Awards

Edusave Award for Achievement, Good Leadership and Service (EAGLES)

Edusave Skills Award

Edusave Merit Bursary

Edusave Merit Bursary

Edusave Merit Bursary and Certificate of Academic Achievement

William Tang

Deliberate Learner | Penultimate Banking and Finance Student | Aspiring Analyst

Singapore

Summary

When was the last time you have dived deep into something and fully immersed yourself in it? To struggle and learn the complexities while enjoying the enriching knowledge that comes with it?

For me, I have decided to dive deep and fully immerse myself in the Banking and Finance industry, and hopefully, many other industries in the future.

My journey first started at the Institute of Technical Education (ITE), where I completed a two-year programme in Higher-Nitec in Banking and Services. During my study term, I was exposed to the financial products and banking procedures carried out by bankers, as well as the various job opportunities. Needless to say, I was captivated. And currently, I am pursuing a Diploma in Banking and Finance at Nanyang Polytechnic.

I also got the opportunity to work at the Singapore College of Insurance (SCI) as a student intern during my time at ITE, where I was further introduced to the insurance industry. Furthermore, I completed my Certificate in General Insurance (CGI), where I learned a multitude of insurance policies, terms, and conditions. And before I knew it, I was already knee-length deep into the Financial Services industry.

As a curious individual, I enjoy participating in workshops and community service, volunteering for leadership roles and picking up both team and individual sports such as judo, running, soccer, and basketball. I had the chance to hone my social and leadership skills, and the ability to work both independently and especially in teams – which I have taken great interest in. Being a goal-oriented and openminded individual, I enjoy connecting with like-minded individuals and working towards a common goal with them; and of course, also

individuals with differing views as well, as I enjoy exploring different insights to broaden my perspective and make friends with them!

Does something in profile appeal to you? Let's connect!

Experience

Pictet Asset Management
Asia Operations Student Intern
February 2023 - August 2023 (7 months)
Singapore

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Trade validation, matching, and confirmation for the various trading desks supported in Singapore, Hong Kong, and Japan.
- Have a full understanding of the operational lifecycle of data and securities within the Asset Management operating model.
- Liaising with brokerage trade support teams across APAC region in the reconciliation of trades.
- Writing of reports: -
- 1. Introduction to Repurchase Agreements
- 2. Introduction to Private Debt
- 3. Middle Office Workflow Process Improvement
- Provide support to the team and undertake any duties as assigned.

Singapore College Of Insurance Student Intern October 2020 - February 2021 (5 months)

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Responsible for collating, tabulating, and analysis of day-to-day data on Microsoft Excel and Word promptly and accurately.
- Responsible for tabulating and analysis of year-to-year data on Microsoft Excel promptly and accurately.
- Responsible for arranging logistics required for daily student examinations in a timely manner.
- Responsible for tabulating and analysis of examination results on a regular basis.
- Responsible for the preparation and disbursement of examination certificates promptly and on a regular basis.
- Helped assisted in facilitating online lectures and ensured the schedule proceeded smoothly.

• Helped assisted in Ad-Hoc projects regularly.

Levis'Store Retail Assistant November 2018 - December 2018 (2 months) Vivo City

- Tidying of the store during opening and closing hours, as well as during shifts.
- Unpacking and re-stocking of products onto shelves and display racks.
- Extensive knowledge in products sold to better help customers make buying decisions.

Education

Nanyang Polytechnic

Diploma in Banking and Finance \cdot (April 2021 - April 2024)